<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Random Ramblings - vehicle</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://copyninja.in/feeds/vehicle.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://copyninja.in/</id><updated>2014-02-22T17:24:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>Random thoughts shooting out of volatile mind</subtitle><entry><title>First experience of driving in Bangalore</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/driving-in-bangalore.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2014-02-22T17:24:00+05:30</published><updated>2014-02-22T17:24:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2014-02-22:/blog/driving-in-bangalore.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Experience of driving 2 wheeler first time in Bangalore&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So finally I did it, I managed to ride the 2-wheeler in Bangalore
roads!. Officially I've got a license to drive 2 and 4 wheelers back
in 2011 but I was never confident enough to ride the vehicle on road
and in traffic. Partially this is because I don't own a vehicle and
I've never practiced driving, and partially because of road and
traffic conditions in India I was bit afraid to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today morning my roommate and me planned to go to temple in the
early morning. We got up at 530 in the morning and we were ready to
drive to Mahalaxmi Layout at 615. Since during this time traffic is
very less I asked my roommate shall I drive and he agreed!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I drove the bike from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malleshwaram"&gt;Malleshwaram&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mahalakshmi_Layout"&gt;Mahalaxmi Layout&lt;/a&gt; and it was fun. I
did had hick up in uphill driving as my mind was not co-ordinating
well with breaks and gear. I did have hickups in first gear too but I
guess this will be alright once I get hold of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still not having enough confidence to drive during the peak hours
because people are not at all following traffic rules. They just
change the lane without any hints or just come to middle of road from
side roads without looking at other side to see if there is a vehicle
is coming from other side of the road (yes they don't have courtesy to
wait). And finally they can shout at persons who is actually following
rules. In general very less people have traffic discipline in
India. But I will adapt to this once I start driving so I'm now all
set to get my 2 wheeler soon and ride on!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="vehicle"/><category term="driving"/><category term="vehicle"/><category term="traffic"/><category term="confidence"/></entry></feed>