<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Random Ramblings - misc</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://copyninja.in/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://copyninja.in/</id><updated>2025-11-16T10:32:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>Random thoughts shooting out of volatile mind</subtitle><entry><title>Moving blog from self hosting to Github Pages</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/move-back-to-github.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2025-11-16T10:32:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-11-16T10:32:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2025-11-16:/blog/move-back-to-github.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Moving the blog to Github pages&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't been blogging as much as I used to. For a while, I've been hosting my
blog on a single-core DigitalOcean droplet, which cost me around $7 per month.
It also hosted my mail server. Most of the time, the droplet was idle, and I
wasn't actively using my personal email much. Since it was self-hosted, I didn't
have confidence that it would always be up, so I relied on Gmail as my personal
email for everything—from banking to social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I feel this cost is just a waste of money, even though it's not huge. So, I
decided to move my blog back to GitHub Pages, now published using GitHub
Workflows. I've stopped my mail server for the time being, and it won't be
reachable for a while. For any personal queries or comments, please reach me on
my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scr.im/vasudev"&gt;Personal Gmail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure how active I'll be with blogging again, but I'll try my best to
return to my old habit of writing at least a post every week or two. Not because
people will read it, but because it gives me the option to explore new things,
experiment, and take notes along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="github"/><category term="pages"/><category term="self-hosting"/></entry><entry><title>Migrating my domain from copyninja.info to copyninja.in</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/migrating_domain.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-06-25T16:13:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-06-25T16:13:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2023-06-25:/blog/migrating_domain.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Just an announcment about domain name move&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After holding the domain &lt;em&gt;copyninja.info&lt;/em&gt; for almost 15 years, I finally let it
expire and bought a new domain, &lt;em&gt;copyninja.in&lt;/em&gt;. With this move, I also bid
goodbye to my VPS, which I had been using for over 12 years on DigitalOcean.
This particular VPS was initially set up with Debian Wheezy (7) and had been
upgraded over the years to successive Debian versions and finally was running
Debian Bullseye (11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason for the move was that the &lt;em&gt;.info&lt;/em&gt; domain was becoming more
expensive every year, and the VPS, which I had upgraded to the $10 USD range,
cost around $12 USD per month with GST included. Since I wasn't really using the
VPS anymore and had recently even broken my DNS and mail server settings, I
decided it was the right time to reduce this additional cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have a cheaper &lt;em&gt;.in&lt;/em&gt; domain, and the VPS is on a minimal configuration at
DigitalOcean, costing $5 USD per month (which becomes almost $7 USD with GST).
Currently, I only run a blog and mail server on this VPS. I will assess if I
really need to keep running the mail server for some more time. If not, I will
move the blog to a hosting service like GitHub Pages and completely get rid of
the VPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My email address has now changed, and the new mail can be obtained from this
&lt;cite&gt;link &amp;lt;http://scr.im/newcopyninj&amp;gt;&lt;/cite&gt;. I have updated my GPG key and added the new
email as the new UID. I still need to revoke the old domain UID. The key has
already been updated in the Debian Keyring.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="domain"/><category term="move"/><category term="newdomain"/></entry><entry><title>Biboumi - A XMPP - IRC Gateway</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/xmpp-irc-gateway.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2018-03-11T10:49:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-11T10:49:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2018-03-11:/blog/xmpp-irc-gateway.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A brief post explaining biboumi and its usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;IRC is a communication mode (technically a communication protocol) used by many
Free Software projects for communication and collaboration. It is serving these
projects well even 30 years after its inception. Though I'm pretty much okay
with IRC I had a problem of not able to use IRC from the mobile phones. Main
problem is the inconsistent network connection, where IRC needs always to be
connected. This is where I came across &lt;em&gt;Biboumi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biboumi&lt;/em&gt; by itself does not have anything to do with mobile phones, its just a
gateway which will allow you to connect with IRC channel as if it is a XMPP MUC
room from any XMPP client. Benefit of this is it allows to enjoy some of XMPP
feature in your IRC channel (not all but those which can be mapped).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run &lt;em&gt;Biboumi&lt;/em&gt; with my &lt;em&gt;ejabbered&lt;/em&gt; instance and there by now I can connect to
some of the &lt;em&gt;Debian&lt;/em&gt; IRC channel directly from my phone using &lt;em&gt;Conversations&lt;/em&gt;
XMPP client for Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biboumi&lt;/em&gt; is packaged for Debian, though I'm co-maintainer of the package most
hardwork is done by &lt;em&gt;Jonas Smedegaard&lt;/em&gt; in keeping the package in shape. It is
also available for &lt;em&gt;stretch-backports&lt;/em&gt; (though slightly outdated as its not
packaged by us for backports). Once you install the package, copy example
configuration file from &lt;cite&gt;/usr/share/doc/biboumi/examples/example.conf&lt;/cite&gt; to
&lt;cite&gt;/etc/biboumi/biboumi.cfg&lt;/cite&gt; and modify the values as needed. Below is my sample
file with password redacted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;hostname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;biboumi.localhost&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;xxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;db_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;/var/lib/biboumi/biboumi.sqlite&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#log_file=/var/log/biboumi/biboumi.log&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;log_level&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;vasudev@copyninja.info&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;8888&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;realname_customization&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;realname_from_jid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explanation for all the key, values in the configuration file is available in
the man page (man biboumi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biboumi is configured as external component of the XMPP server. In
my case I'm using ejabberd to host my XMPP service. Below is the configuration
needed for allowing biboumi to connect with ejabberd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;listen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p p-Indicator"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;8888&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;ip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;127.0.0.1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;ejabberd_service&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;acess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;hosts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;biboumi.localhost&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p p-Indicator"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;xxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;password&lt;/cite&gt; field in biboumi configuration should match password value in your
XMPP server configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing above configuration reload ejabberd (or your XMPP server) and start
biboumi. Biboumi package provides systemd service file so you might need to
enable it first. That's it now you have an XMPP to IRC gateway ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice that I'm using local host name for &lt;em&gt;hostname&lt;/em&gt; key as well as
&lt;em&gt;ip&lt;/em&gt; field in ejabberd configuration. This is because TLS support was added to
&lt;em&gt;biboumi&lt;/em&gt; Debian package only after 7.2 release as botan 2.x was not available
till that point in Debian. Hence using proper domain name and making biboumi
listen to public will be not safe at least prior to Debian package version
7.2-2. Also making the biboumi service public means you will also need to handle
spam bots trying to connect from your service to IRC, which might get your VPS
banned from IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="connection-semantics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Connection Semantics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once biboumi is configured and running you can now use XMPP client of your
choice (Gajim, Conversation etc.) to connect to IRC. To connect to OFTC from
your XMPP client you need to following address in &lt;em&gt;Group Chat&lt;/em&gt; section&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;%irc.oftc.net&amp;#64;biboumi.localhost&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace part after &amp;#64; to what you have configured in &lt;em&gt;hostname&lt;/em&gt; field in biboumi
configuration. To join a specific channel on a IRC server you need to join the
group conversation with following format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;#channel%irc.example.com&amp;#64;biboumi.localhost&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your nick name is registered and you would want to identify yourself to IRC
server you can do that by joining in group conversation with NickServ using
following address&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;nickserv%irc.example.org&amp;#64;biboumi.localhost&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once connected you can send NickServ command directly in this virtual channel.
Like &lt;cite&gt;identify password nick&lt;/cite&gt;. It is also possible to configure your XMPP
clients like Gajim to send &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0050.html"&gt;Ad-Hoc commands&lt;/a&gt; on connection to particular IRC
server for identifying your self with IRC servers. But this part I did not get
working in Gajim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are running your own XMPP server then &lt;em&gt;biboumi&lt;/em&gt; gives you best way to
connect to IRC from your mobile phones. And with applications like
&lt;em&gt;Conversation&lt;/em&gt; running XMPP application won't be hard on your phone battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://lab.louiz.org/louiz/biboumi/blob/master/doc/biboumi.1.rst#configuration"&gt;Biboumi documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conversations.im/"&gt;Conversations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.ejabberd.im/admin/configuration/"&gt;ejabberd documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="xmpp"/><category term="irc"/><category term="gateway"/><category term="mobile"/></entry><entry><title>Magic: Attach a HTML file to mail and get different on other side</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/fun-with-html-encoding.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2017-05-06T13:19:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-05-06T13:19:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2017-05-06:/blog/fun-with-html-encoding.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Magic happens when you attach HTML with certain format in mail and
find totally different file on other end.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time I did not write any new blog posts, and finally I got
something which is interesting enough for a new post and so here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually wanted some bills from my ISP for some work and I could not find mail
from the ISP which had bills for some specific months in my mailbox. Problem
with my ISP is bills are accessible in their account which can be only accessed
from their own network. They do have a mobile app and that does not seem to work
especially for the billing section. I used mobile app and selected month for
which I did not have bill and clicked &lt;em&gt;Send Mail&lt;/em&gt; button. App happily showed
message saying it sent the bill to my registered mail address but that was a
fancy lie. After trying several time I gave up and decided I will do it once I
get back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward few hours, I'm back home from office and then I sat in front of my
laptop and connected to ISP site, promptly downloaded the bills, then used
&lt;em&gt;notmuch-emacs&lt;/em&gt; and fire up a mail composer, attach those HTML file (yeah they
produce bill in HTML file :-/) send it to my gmail and forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward few more days, I just remember I need those bills. I got hold of
mail I sent earlier in gmail inbox and clicked on attachment and when browser
opened the attachment I was shocked/surprised . Did you ask why?. See what I saw
when I opened attachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://copyninja.in/images/converted_html.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I was confused for moment on what happened, I tried downloading the file
and opened it an editor, and I see Chinese characters here also. After reaching
home I checked the Sent folder in my laptop where I keep copy of mails sent
using &lt;em&gt;notmuch-emacs&lt;/em&gt;'s &lt;cite&gt;notmuch-fcc-dirs&lt;/cite&gt; variable. I open the file and open
the attachement and I see same character as I saw in browser!. I open the
original bills I downloaded and it looks fine. To check if I really attached the
correct files I again drafted a mail this time to my personal email and sent it.
Now I open the file from Sent folder and voila again there is different content
inside my attachment!. Same happens when I receive the mail and open the
attachment everything inside is Chinese characters!. Totally lost I finally
opened the original file using &lt;em&gt;emacs&lt;/em&gt;, since I use &lt;em&gt;spacemacs&lt;/em&gt; it asked me for
downloading of &lt;em&gt;html layer&lt;/em&gt; and after which I was surprised because everything
inside the editor is in Chinese!. OK finally I've something now so I opened same
file at same time in &lt;em&gt;nano&lt;/em&gt; from terminal and there it looks fine!. OK that is
weird again I read carefully content and saw this line in beginning of file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-16&amp;quot; ?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;xmlns=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;....
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK that is new XML tag had encoding declared as &lt;em&gt;UTF-16&lt;/em&gt;, really?. And just for
checking I changed it to UTF-8 and voila file is back to normal in Emacs
window!. To confirm this behavior I created a sample file with following content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;xmlns&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;http-equiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Content-Type&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;text/html; charset=iso-8859-1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; Something weird &lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;blablablablablalabkabakba&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah with long line because ISP had similar case and now I opened the same file
in nano using terminal and changed &lt;cite&gt;encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot;&lt;/cite&gt; to &lt;cite&gt;encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-16&amp;quot;&lt;/cite&gt; and
the behavior repeated I see Chinese character in the emacs buffer which has also
opened the same file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the small gif showing this happening in real time, see what happens in
emacs buffer when I change the encoding in terminal below. Fun right?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://copyninja.in/images/html_weirdness.gif" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made following observation from above experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I open original file in browser or my sample file with
&lt;cite&gt;encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-16&amp;quot;&lt;/cite&gt; its normal, no Chinese characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I attach the mail and send it out the attachment some how gets converted
into HTML file with Chinese characters and viewing source from browser shows
header containing xml declarations and original &lt;cite&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/cite&gt; declarations get
ripped off and new tags show up which I've pasted below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I download the same file and open in editor only Chinese characters are
present and no HTML tags inside it. So definitely the new tags which I saw by
viewing source in browser is added by Firefox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I create similar HTML file and change encoding I can see the characters
changing back and forth in emacs &lt;em&gt;web-mode&lt;/em&gt; when I change encoding of the
file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC &amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;META&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;http-equiv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Content-Type&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="na"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if I'm understanding this correctly, &lt;em&gt;Emacs&lt;/em&gt; due to encoding declaration
interprets the actual contents differently. To see how &lt;em&gt;Emacs&lt;/em&gt; really
interpreted the content I opened the sent mail I had in raw format and saw
following header lines for attachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;Content-Type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;text/html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;; charset=utf-8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;Content-Disposition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;attachment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;             &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;filename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;SOA-102012059675-FEBRUARY-2017.html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;Content-Transfer-Encoding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;base64&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was followed with base64 encoded data. So does this mean emacs interpreted
the content as UTF-16 and encoded the content using UTF-8?. Again I've no clue,
so I changed the &lt;cite&gt;encoding&lt;/cite&gt; in both the files to be as UTF-8 and sent the mail
by attaching these files again to see what happens. And my guess was right I
could get the attachment as is on the receiving side. And inspecting raw mail
the attachment headers now different than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;Content-Type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;text/html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;Content-Disposition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;attachment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;             &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;filename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;SOA-102012059675-DECEMBER-2016.html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;Content-Transfer-Encoding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;quoted-printable&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how &lt;em&gt;Content-Type&lt;/em&gt; its different now also see the
&lt;em&gt;Content-Transfer-Encoding&lt;/em&gt; its now &lt;cite&gt;quoted-printable&lt;/cite&gt; as opposed to &lt;cite&gt;base64&lt;/cite&gt;
earlier. Additionally I can see HTML content below the header.
When I opened the attachment from mail I get the actual bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I understand base64 encoding is used when the data to be attached is
base64. So I guess basically due to wrong encoding declared inside the file
&lt;em&gt;Emacs&lt;/em&gt; interpreted the content as a binary data and encoded it differently than
what it really should be. Phew that was a lot of investigation to understand the
magic but it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do let me know your thoughts on this.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="html"/><category term="encoding"/></entry><entry><title>Stop messing with my settings Network Manager</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/networkmanager-wifi-issue.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2014-07-20T00:39:00+05:30</published><updated>2014-07-20T00:39:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2014-07-20:/blog/networkmanager-wifi-issue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Network Manager toying with wifi card&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use a laptop with &lt;cite&gt;Atheros&lt;/cite&gt; wifi card with &lt;cite&gt;ath9k&lt;/cite&gt; driver. I use
&lt;cite&gt;hostapd&lt;/cite&gt; to convert my laptop wifi into AP (Access point) so I can
share network with my &lt;cite&gt;Nexus 7&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;Kindle&lt;/cite&gt;. This has been working
fine for quite some time till my recent update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After recent system update (I use Debian Sid), I couldn't for some
reason convert my wifi into AP so my device can connect. I can't find
anything in log nor in hostapd debug messages which is useful to
trouble shoot the issue. Every time I start the laptop my wifi card
will be blocked by RF-KILL and I have manually unblock (both hard and
soft). The script which I use to convert my Wifi into AP is below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;#Initial wifi interface configuration
ifconfig &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot; up 192.168.2.1 netmask 255.255.255.0
sleep 2

# start dhcp
sudo systemctl restart dnsmasq.service

iptables --flush
iptables --table nat --flush
iptables --delete-chain
iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o &amp;quot;$2&amp;quot; -j MASQUERADE
iptables -A FORWARD -i &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot; -j ACCEPT

sysctl -w net.ipv4.ip_forward=1

#start hostapd
hostapd /etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf  &amp;amp;&amp;gt; /dev/null &amp;amp;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried rebooting the laptop and for some time I managed to convert my
wifi into AP, I noticed at same time that Network Manager is not
started once laptop is booted, yeah this also started happening after
recent upgrade which I guess is the black magic of systemd. After some
time I noticed wifi has went down and now I can't bring it up because
its blocked by RF-KILL. After checking the syslog I noticed following
lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra kernel: [ 1754.891060] IPv6: ADDRCONF(NETDEV_CHANGE): wlan0: link becomes ready
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; (mon.wlan0): using nl80211 for WiFi device control
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; (mon.wlan0): driver supports Access Point (AP) mode
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; (mon.wlan0): new 802.11 WiFi device (driver: 'ath9k' ifindex: 10)
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; (mon.wlan0): exported as /org/freedesktop/NetworkManager/Devices/8
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; (mon.wlan0): device state change: unmanaged -&amp;gt; unavailable (reason 'managed') [10 20 2]
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; (mon.wlan0): preparing device
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; devices added (path: /sys/devices/pci0000:00/0000:00:1c.1/0000:04:00.0/net/mon.wlan0, iface: mon.wlan0)
Jul 18 23:09:30 rudra NetworkManager[5485]: &amp;lt;info&amp;gt; device added (path: /sys/devices/pci0000:00/0000:00:1c.1/0000:04:00.0/net/mon.wlan0, iface: mon.wlan0): no ifupdown configuration found.
Jul 18 23:09:33 rudra ModemManager[891]: &amp;lt;warn&amp;gt;  Couldn't find support for device at '/sys/devices/pci0000:00/0000:00:1c.1/0000:04:00.0': not supported by any plugin
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I couldn't figure out much but it looks like NetworkManager has
come up and after seeing interface &lt;cite&gt;mon.wlan0&lt;/cite&gt;, a monitoring interface
created by &lt;cite&gt;hostapd&lt;/cite&gt; to monitor the AP goes mad and tries to do
something with it. I've no clue what it is doing and don't have enough
patience to debug that. Probably some expert can give me hints on
this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as a last resort I purged the NetworkManager completely from the
system and settled back to good old &lt;cite&gt;wicd&lt;/cite&gt; and rebooted the
system. After reboot wifi card is happy and is not blocked by RF-KILL
and now I can convert it AP and use it as long as I wish without any
problems. Wicd is not a great tool but its good enough to get the job
done and does only what is asked to it unlike the NetworkManager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in short&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
NetworkManager please stop f***ing with my settings and stop acting
oversmart.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="network-manager"/><category term="ath9k"/><category term="wifi"/></entry><entry><title>Kontalk FLOSS alternative for Whatsapp and Co.</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/kontalk-messaging.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2014-02-21T19:51:00+05:30</published><updated>2014-02-21T19:51:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2014-02-21:/blog/kontalk-messaging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;FLOSS alternative for Whatsapp.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So &lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt; has been acquired by Facebook and this news is still hot
and people are discussing it all over the twitterverse. So I took this
opportunity to stop using &lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt; and removed it from my
phone. Possibly I could have deleted my account but who cares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway I've been searching for a secure and FLOSS alternative for
&lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt; for quite some time now, few days ago I found about
&lt;em&gt;Telegram&lt;/em&gt; but after reading &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.tincho.org/posts/Telegram/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by Tincho on planet Debian,
I decided not to use it.  Recently while going through the talk list
for fossmeet.in I found link for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kontalk.org"&gt;Kontalk&lt;/a&gt; in a
privacy awareness talk &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://funnel.fossmeet.in/2014/61-i-have-nothing-to-hide-i-dont-care-about-privacy"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;
by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qa.debian.org/developer.php?login=praveen"&gt;Praveen&lt;/a&gt; and
thought I should give it a try.  So below is my first feelings about
&lt;em&gt;Kontalk&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installation-and-activation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation and Activation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kontalk can be installed from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.kontalk"&gt;playstore&lt;/a&gt; for
verification purpose it requests your phone number and country code
and request for verification. This should send a SMS with a code which
should be entered in the text box given and app is ready to use. There
is also a possibility to use pre-existing verification code (if you
got one from developer directly, read below for details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did see some glitches like I never got the SMS delivered to my phone
after 2 attempts and a days wait. Then I went ahead and reported a
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/kontalk/issues/detail?id=179"&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; and
the main developer was quick to respond. After a discussion it was
noticed that SMS was blocked by spam filters. He also mentioned its
tough to get SMS delivered to India. He was kind enough to provide me
with a verification code and I used the &lt;em&gt;Use existing code&lt;/em&gt; option to
enter it and get &lt;em&gt;Kontalk&lt;/em&gt; activated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SMS delivery inconsistency is still present for India (and may be
other nations too) some people get code immidiately others may be
after couple of days and some might not. Upstream is already working
on a possible &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/kontalk/issues/detail?id=141"&gt;workaround&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="user-experience"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now coming to usage part, the UI is neat and clean, I won't say super
polished as &lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt; or other popular apps but its really &lt;em&gt;neat&lt;/em&gt; and
easy to use. Some points which I like are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to hide presence, so others won't know you are online or
offline. (unlike &lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt; which advertises last seen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypted messages and ability to optin or optout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypted status messages! Only user with your phone number can see
your status. (Cool isn't it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually requesting to find contacts who already uses
kontalk!. Right it doesn't read your contact list without your
permission you need to refresh to check who in your contacts is
using Kontalk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attach and smiley options in the top right corner of Chat window
which allows easy accessing unlike keyboard - smiley switching of
&lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No automatic download of media contents which is shared. Yes by
default it doesn't download any picture or video automatically if
you want to see something click on it and select download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running your own server for Kontalk! Now thats something which is
interesting for people who doesn't want to host their data on some
other peoples infrastructure. Code for server is available at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/kontalk/source/browse?repo=xmppserver"&gt;xmppserver&lt;/a&gt;
repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are some rough edges also but I'm sure this can be
improved. But some points which I noticed are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact name disappears and only number is displayed. This is
something which happened with one of my contact so I'm not really
sure its a bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My friend noticed all his existing contacts suddenly vanished when
he refreshed contacts list. Again this is possible bugs and we are
considering reporting it upstream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No group chats yet. I don't see a option to do that yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attachment at the moment is restricted only to pictures (and video?
never tried) and uploading takes quite sometime and sometime hangs
forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm considering forwarding these to upstream and help them by
providing enough data so these can be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="technical-side"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Side&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All code for client server and protocol specs are available under
GPL-v3 at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/kontalk"&gt;Kontalk project&lt;/a&gt;
site. Server software is written in Python and I guess uses XMPP (but
I've not cross verified). Server also uses MySQL as database. These
can be hosted on our own servers but possibly needs more than that
like SMS sending options etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my views &lt;em&gt;Kontalk&lt;/em&gt; can become a great alternative for &lt;em&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/em&gt;
and co from Free Software world and I encourage every one to give it a
try which will be the first step to help improving it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Disclaimer: I'm not a privacy or security expert so whatever I shared
above are what I noticed and experts may see something different than
this. In any case I welcome comments and suggestions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="smartphone"/><category term="messaging"/><category term="whatsapp"/><category term="foss"/></entry><entry><title>Friendica instance on my VPS is down</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/friendica-instance-down.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2014-02-08T20:31:00+05:30</published><updated>2014-02-08T20:31:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2014-02-08:/blog/friendica-instance-down.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Friendica instance on my vps went down.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started running &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://friendica.com"&gt;Friendica&lt;/a&gt; instance on my
VPS. With help of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dr.jones.dk"&gt;Jonas Smedegaard&lt;/a&gt; I managed
to run Friendica in a uWSGI container. The site was running at
&lt;em&gt;samsargika.copyninja.info&lt;/em&gt; and is no longer accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since VPS itself was running Debian Wheezy I couldn't run uWSGI with
PHP support on it. &lt;em&gt;(support for PHP in uWSGI landed after
Wheezy)&lt;/em&gt;. But Jonas was kind enough for me to provide a backported
version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Wheezy got a security update for PHP and thats where all the
problem started. The backported &lt;em&gt;uwsgi-plugin-php&lt;/em&gt; was not recompiled
to use security updated PHP and I couldn't upgrade the things. After
few days I noticed first freeze on my VPS and I had to reboot the VPS
to get it online again. The fact I noticed was uWSGI being killed due
to a OOM in syslog but I didn't explore much and consulted Jonas to
get a updated uWSGI. But that didn't happen as Jonas himself is facing
some problem with uWSGI builds. While again checking with aptitude for
upgrade I accidentally confirmed removal of &lt;em&gt;uwsgi-plugin-php&lt;/em&gt; for
getting security updates :-/. But nothing happened to my running
service as upgrade of libs in Debian doesn't cause the restart of all
services which are using that lib &lt;em&gt;(desired effect is restart of
service but I don't know the side affects involved)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second freeze happened yesterday and on the reboot &lt;em&gt;uwsgi-plugin-php&lt;/em&gt;
was missing there by taking my Friendica instance down. More closer
investigation showed the same OOM but this time I noticed each OOM
occurred just after cronjob was running &lt;em&gt;poller.php&lt;/em&gt; a script which is
actually causing all federation in Friendica. So it was clear there is
something wrong either in &lt;em&gt;poller.php&lt;/em&gt; or in my setup which was making
it eat memory and freeze my VPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also found some stupidity I did during configuration which Jonas
also pointed me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Installing cronjob inside crontab rather than cron.d&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Installing poller.php crontab for root user :-/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically violated the basic rule by running a unsafe script as root
user, good that script didn't do some crazy stuff. So even though my
instance went down I learnt my lessons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don't ever ever ever run a unsafe script as root that too through cron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandbox the unsafe script so it can be killed on time rather than
it taking the whole system down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;PHP is not really secure, if it was secure there wouldn't be
security updates and atleast my site would be still running :-D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I now need to wait till Jonas get me new shiny backported uWSGI
linked against new PHP on Wheezy and till that time I need to explore
on how I can sandbox the poller.php script.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="friendica"/><category term="sysadmin"/><category term="php"/><category term="debian"/><category term="sandboxing"/></entry><entry><title>Moving weblog from Jekyll to Pelican</title><link href="https://copyninja.in/blog/blog-move.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2014-02-02T08:55:00+05:30</published><updated>2014-02-02T08:55:00+05:30</updated><author><name>copyninja</name></author><id>tag:copyninja.in,2014-02-02:/blog/blog-move.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Re-creating blog using Pelican&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Its been a while and I was not actively blogging. I wanted to start
blogging again but I was for some reason not happy with &lt;em&gt;Jekyll&lt;/em&gt;
static site generator which was powering my previous site. So I took
this chance to explore other static site generators and redesign my
blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explored a bit of Pelican, Nikola and Frog. I didn't feel
comfortable with &lt;em&gt;Nikola&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Frog&lt;/em&gt; is a static site generator written
using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://racket-lang.org/"&gt;*Racket*&lt;/a&gt; and since I'm learning
Scheme using racket I was leaning towards using it but at the last
moment I decided to settle with &lt;em&gt;Pelican&lt;/em&gt;. The main reason for not
using &lt;em&gt;Frog&lt;/em&gt; was that I just wanted to get my site up rather than
waiting for me to complete learning racket and use Frog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feeling about Pelican is that its a nice tool and is simple and
gives all basic things like generating RSS/ATOM feeds and nice theming
support. In case of Jekyll I had to write custom page for creating RSS
feed and had pain in creating my first theme (yeah I'm not a
designer). But now things might have changed in Jekyll land but anyway
I don't care anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New design uses &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/DandyDev/pelican-bootstrap3"&gt;pelican-bootstrap3&lt;/a&gt; theme and there is
no comment facility available. If you want to comment or suggesting
things on my post consider writing mail to me :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happened to older entries? Moving the old entries from Jekyll
format to Pelican was real PITA so I just renamed my old site to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog-archive.copyninja.info"&gt;blog-archive&lt;/a&gt;. So this is a
from scratch site and will contain only new entries. So how do you
like my new blog design? :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="misc"/><category term="jekyll"/><category term="pelican"/><category term="blog"/></entry></feed>